<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RecipeBook</string>
    <string name="homepage_title">Kitchen Chronicles</string>
    <string-array name="recipes">
        <item name="recipe_one">Mexican Burrito</item>
        <item name="recipe_two">Chicken Katsu Curry</item>
        <item name="recipe_three">Waakye</item>
        <item name="recipe_four">Lasagne</item>
        <item name="recipe_five">Lamb Biryani</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="burrito_description">A delicious, customizable burrito packed
        with fluffy rice, savory beans, tender protein, and fresh toppings.
        Perfect for lunch or dinner, it’s easy to make, satisfying, and
        bursting with flavors in every bite. Wrap it up and enjoy a handheld
        meal that’s both hearty and comforting.</string>
    <string name="ingredients"> Ingredients: </string>
    <string-array name="burrito_ingredients">
        <item> 1 cup black beans (cooked)</item>
        <item> 2 large flour tortillas</item>
        <item> 1 cup cooked rice</item>
        <item> 1 cup cooked chicken or beef (optional)</item>
        <item> ½ cup shredded cheese</item>
        <item> ¼ cup salsa </item>
        <item> ¼ cup sour cream </item>
        <item> Lettuce, chopped</item>
        <item>1 tbsp olive oil </item>
        <item>Salt and pepper to taste </item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="steps">Steps:</string>
    <string-array name="burrito_steps">
        <item> Heat olive oil in a pan over medium heat.</item>
        <item> Warm tortillas for 20–30 seconds on each side. </item>
        <item> Lay the tortilla flat and layer rice, beans, and protein in the center.</item>
        <item> Sprinkle shredded cheese on top.</item>
        <item> Add salsa, sour cream, and lettuce.</item>
        <item> Fold the sides of the tortilla inwards, then roll it tightly from the bottom.</item>
        <item> Serve warm, optionally cut in half. </item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="chicken_katsu_curry_description"> Chicken katsu curry is a popular Japanese comfort dish
        consisting of a crispy, panko-breaded chicken cutlet served with a sweet, mild, and aromatic
        Japanese curry sauce, typically over a bed of white rice. The chicken is deeply fried until
        golden brown, contrasting with the smooth, luxurious texture of the warm, fruity curry. </string>
    <string-array name="chicken_katsu_curry_ingredients">
        <item> Chicken breasts </item>
        <item> Salt and pepper </item>
        <item> Flour, eggs, panko breadcrumbs </item>
        <item> Oil (for frying) </item>
        <item> Onion, carrot, garlic, ginger </item>
        <item> Curry powder, flour, chicken stock </item>
        <item> Soy sauce, honey, ketchup </item>
        <item> Rice (to serve) </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="chicken_katsu_curry_steps">
        <item> Pound chicken breasts until even thickness.</item>
        <item> Season with salt and pepper. </item>
        <item> Coat each piece in flour → dip in beaten egg → coat in panko breadcrumbs.</item>
        <item>Fry in hot oil (about 170–180 °C / 340–355 °F) until golden brown and cooked through.
            Drain on paper towel. Sauté chopped onion, carrot, garlic, and ginger in a little oil until soft.</item>
        <item> Stir in curry powder and flour, cook 1 min.</item>
        <item> Gradually add chicken stock, stirring until smooth.</item>
        <item> Add soy sauce, honey, and ketchup. Simmer 10–15 mins until thickened. </item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="waakye_description"> Waakye is a Ghanaian dish of rice and beans,
        cooked with sorghum leaves (waakye leaves) that give it a brown color and earthy flavor.
        It’s usually served with sides like stew, shito (spicy sauce), fried plantain, spaghetti,
        gari, boiled eggs, and meat or fish — making it a hearty, complete meal.</string>
    <string-array name="waakye_ingredients">
        <item> Beans (traditionally black-eyed peas)</item>
        <item> Rice (white rice like jasmine or basmati) </item>
        <item> Sorghum Leaves (Waakye Leaves) </item>
        <item> Salt </item>
        <item> Coconut Oil </item>
        <item> Baking Soda or Kaun </item>
        <item> Stew (tomato-based, with meat, fish, or shito) </item>
        <item> Boiled Eggs </item>
        <item> Salad (cabbage, onions, tomatoes) </item>
        <item> Spaghetti (Talia) </item>
        <item> Fried Plantains </item>
        <item> Garri (ground cassava flakes) </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="waakye_steps">
        <item> Soak and cook beans with waakye leaves (or a pinch of baking soda) until tender.</item>
        <item> Add rice to the beans, season with salt, and cook until rice is soft and water is absorbed.</item>
        <item> Remove leaves, fluff, and serve with sides like stew, shito, plantain, boiled eggs, or meat/fish</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="lasagne_description">Lasagne is a classic Italian baked pasta dish made of layers
        of wide flat pasta sheets, rich meat or vegetable sauce, creamy béchamel or ricotta cheese,
        and melted cheese on top. It’s hearty, flavorful, and perfect for family meals or special occasions.</string>
    <string-array name="lasagne_ingredients">
        <item> 500g ground beef (or a mix of beef and pork) </item>
        <item> 1 onion, finely chopped </item>
        <item> 2 garlic cloves, minced </item>
        <item> 400g canned tomatoes (or fresh, chopped) </item>
        <item> 1 tsp dried oregano </item>
        <item> 1 tsp dried basil </item>
        <item> Salt and pepper, to taste </item>
        <item> 2 tbsp olive oil </item>
        <item> 50g butter </item>
        <item> 50g all-purpose flour </item>
        <item> 500ml milk </item>
        <item> Pinch of nutmeg </item>
        <item> 9–12 lasagne sheets (pre-cooked or no-boil type) </item>
        <item> 200g grated mozzarella cheese </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="lasagne_steps">
        <item> Preheat oven to 180°C (350°F).</item>
        <item> Cook onions and garlic in olive oil until soft.</item>
        <item> Add ground meat, cook until browned, then stir in tomatoes, tomato paste, herbs, salt,
            and pepper; simmer 15–20 minutes.</item>
        <item> Make béchamel: melt butter, whisk in flour, gradually add milk, season with salt, pepper, and nutmeg. </item>
        <item> Layer meat sauce, lasagne sheets, béchamel, and mozzarella in a baking dish; repeat
            and top with béchamel, mozzarella, and Parmesan. </item>
        <item> Layer meat sauce, lasagne sheets, béchamel, and mozzarella in a baking dish; repeat
            and top with béchamel, mozzarella, and Parmesan. </item>
        <item> Cover with foil and bake 25 minutes, remove foil and bake 15 more minutes until golden. </item>
        <item> Let rest 10 minutes, then serve </item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="lamb_biryani_description">Lamb biryani is a fragrant and flavorful South Asian
        rice dish made by layering tender, spiced lamb with long-grain basmati rice, aromatic herbs,
        and sometimes saffron or fried onions. It is slow-cooked to allow the flavors to meld,
        resulting in a rich, savory, and slightly spicy meal that is both hearty and aromatic,
        often served with raita, salad, or chutney.</string>
    <string-array name="lamb_biryani_ingredients">
        <item> 500g lamb, cut into chunks </item>
        <item> 2 cups basmati rice </item>
        <item> 2 large onions, thinly sliced </item>
        <item> 2 tomatoes, chopped </item>
        <item> 4 cloves garlic, minced </item>
        <item> 1-inch piece ginger, grated </item>
        <item> 1 cup yogurt </item>
        <item> 3 tbsp cooking oil or ghee </item>
        <item> 1 tsp cumin seeds </item>
        <item> 2 green chilies, slit </item>
        <item> 1 tsp garam masala </item>
        <item> Fresh coriander </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="lamb_biryani_steps">
        <item> Mix lamb chunks with yogurt, turmeric, chili powder, and salt. Let it sit for 30 minutes.</item>
        <item> Boil water with a pinch of salt and whole spices (cardamom, cloves, cinnamon).
            Cook rice until 70% done, then drain.</item>
        <item> Heat oil/ghee in a large pan, sauté cumin seeds, garlic, ginger, and green chilies.
            Add onions and cook until golden brown.</item>
        <item> Add marinated lamb to the pan, cook until the lamb is browned and partially cooked.
            Add tomatoes, coriander powder, and garam masala. Simmer until lamb is tender. </item>
        <item> In a large pot, layer half the rice, then the lamb mixture, then the remaining rice.
            Sprinkle fresh coriander and mint leaves on top. </item>
        <item> Cover tightly and cook on very low heat for 20–25 minutes to let flavors meld. </item>
    </string-array>

</resources>